<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><search><entry><title>Markdown语法手册</title><url>/2019/03/11/markdown%E8%AF%AD%E6%B3%95%E6%89%8B%E5%86%8C/</url><categories><category>themes</category><category>syntax</category></categories><tags><tag>markdown</tag><tag>css</tag><tag>html</tag></tags><content type="html"> 本文提供了一个可以在Hugo内容文件中使用的基本Markdown语法示例，还展示了基本HTML元素在Hugo主题中是否使用CSS装饰。
Headings The following HTML &lt;h1>—&lt;h6> elements represent six levels of section headings. &lt;h1> is the highest section level while &lt;h6> is the lowest.
H1 H2 H3 H4 H5 H6 Paragraph Xerum, quo qui aut unt expliquam qui dolut labo. Aque venitatiusda cum, voluptionse latur sitiae dolessi aut parist aut dollo enim qui voluptate ma dolestendit peritin re plis aut quas inctum laceat est volestemque commosa as cus endigna tectur, offic to cor sequas etum rerum idem sintibus eiur? Quianimin porecus evelectur, cum que nis nust voloribus ratem aut omnimi, sitatur? Quiatem. Nam, omnis sum am facea corem alique molestrunt et eos evelece arcillit ut aut eos eos nus, sin conecerem erum fuga. Ri oditatquam, ad quibus unda veliamenimin cusam et facea ipsamus es exerum sitate dolores editium rerore eost, temped molorro ratiae volorro te reribus dolorer sperchicium faceata tiustia prat.
Itatur? Quiatae cullecum rem ent aut odis in re eossequodi nonsequ idebis ne sapicia is sinveli squiatum, core et que aut hariosam ex eat.
Blockquotes The blockquote element represents content that is quoted from another source, optionally with a citation which must be within a footer or cite element, and optionally with in-line changes such as annotations and abbreviations.
Blockquote without attribution Tiam, ad mint andaepu dandae nostion secatur sequo quae. Note that you can use Markdown syntax within a blockquote.
Blockquote with attribution Don&rsquo;t communicate by sharing memory, share memory by communicating.— Rob Pike1 Tables Tables aren&rsquo;t part of the core Markdown spec, but Hugo supports supports them out-of-the-box.
Name Age Bob 27 Alice 23 Inline Markdown within tables Italics Bold Code italics bold code Code Blocks Code block with backticks &lt;!doctype html> &lt;html lang="en"> &lt;head> &lt;meta charset="utf-8"> &lt;title>Example HTML5 Document&lt;/title> &lt;/head> &lt;body> &lt;p>Test&lt;/p> &lt;/body> &lt;/html> Code block indented with four spaces &lt;!doctype html> &lt;html lang="en"> &lt;head> &lt;meta charset="utf-8"> &lt;title>Example HTML5 Document&lt;/title> &lt;/head> &lt;body> &lt;p>Test&lt;/p> &lt;/body> &lt;/html> Code block with Hugo&rsquo;s internal highlight shortcode &lt;!doctype html> &lt;html lang="en"> &lt;head> &lt;meta charset="utf-8"> &lt;title>Example HTML5 Document&lt;/title> &lt;/head> &lt;body> &lt;p>Test&lt;/p> &lt;/body> &lt;/html> List Types Ordered List First item Second item Third item Unordered List List item Another item And another item Nested list Fruit Apple Orange Banana Dairy Milk Cheese Other Elements — abbr, sub, sup, kbd, mark GIFis a bitmap image format.
H2O
Xn+ Yn= ZnPress CTRL+ALT+Deleteto end the session.
Most salamandersare nocturnal, and hunt for insects, worms, and other small creatures.
The above quote is excerpted from Rob Pike&rsquo;s talk during Gopherfest, November 18, 2015. &#8617;&#xfe0e;</content></entry><entry><title>富文本内容测试</title><url>/2019/03/10/%E5%AF%8C%E6%96%87%E6%9C%AC%E5%86%85%E5%AE%B9%E6%B5%8B%E8%AF%95/</url><categories/><tags><tag>shortcodes</tag><tag>privacy</tag></tags><content type="html"> Hugo 雨果附带几个[内置的短码](https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/ use-hugos-built-in-shortcodes)内容丰富,以及隐私配置和一组简单的短码,使静态和no-JS版本的各种社会媒体嵌入。
YouTube Privacy Enhanced Shortcode Twitter Simple Shortcode .twitter-tweet { font: 14px/1.45 -apple-system,BlinkMacSystemFont,"Segoe UI",Roboto,Oxygen-Sans,Ubuntu,Cantarell,"Helvetica Neue",sans-serif; border-left: 4px solid #2b7bb9; padding-left: 1.5em; color: #555; } .twitter-tweet a { color: #2b7bb9; text-decoration: none; } blockquote.twitter-tweet a:hover, blockquote.twitter-tweet a:focus { text-decoration: underline; } “In addition to being more logical, asymmetry has the advantage that its complete appearance is far more optically effective than symmetry.”
— Jan Tschichold pic.twitter.com/gcv7SrhvJb
&mdash; Graphic Design History (@DesignReviewed) January 17, 2019 Vimeo Simple Shortcode .__h_video { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.23%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; width: 100%; background: #000; } .__h_video img { width: 100%; height: auto; color: #000; } .__h_video .play { height: 72px; width: 72px; left: 50%; top: 50%; margin-left: -36px; margin-top: -36px; position: absolute; cursor: pointer; }</content></entry><entry><title>占位符文本显示</title><url>/2019/03/09/%E5%8D%A0%E4%BD%8D%E7%AC%A6%E6%96%87%E6%9C%AC%E6%98%BE%E7%A4%BA/</url><categories/><tags><tag>markdown</tag><tag>text</tag></tags><content type="html"> 你对我的心有偏见。我向您保证，我们的生活将不会受到影响，我们的生活将会受到影响。你说你现在住在医院里，因为你的眼睛是透明的，你的眼睛是光明的，你的眼睛是光明的!
Exierant elisi ambit vivere dedere Duce pollice Eris modo Spargitque ferrea quos palude Rursus nulli murmur; hastile inridet ut ab gravi sententia! Nomine potitus silentia flumen, sustinet placuit petis in dilapsa erat sunt. Atria tractus malis.
Comas hunc haec pietate fetum procerum dixit Post torum vates letum Tiresia Flumen querellas Arcanaque montibus omnes Quidem et Vagus elidunt The Van de Graaf Canon
Mane refeci capiebant unda mulcebat Victa caducifer, malo vulnere contra dicere aurato, ludit regale, voca! Retorsit colit est profanae esse virescere furit nec; iaculi matertera et visa est, viribus. Divesque creatis, tecta novat collumque vulnus est, parvas. Faces illo pepulere tempus adest. Tendit flamma, ab opes virum sustinet, sidus sequendo urbis.
Iubar proles corpore raptos vero auctor imperium; sed et huic: manus caeli Lelegas tu lux. Verbis obstitit intus oblectamina fixis linguisque ausus sperare Echionides cornuaque tenent clausit possit. Omnia putatur. Praeteritae refert ausus; ferebant e primus lora nutat, vici quae mea ipse. Et iter nil spectatae vulnus haerentia iuste et exercebat, sui et.
Eurytus Hector, materna ipsumque ut Politen, nec, nate, ignari, vernum cohaesit sequitur. Vel mitis temploque vocatus, inque alis, oculos nomen non silvis corpore coniunx ne displicet illa. Crescunt non unus, vidit visa quantum inmiti flumina mortis facto sic: undique a alios vincula sunt iactata abdita! Suspenderat ego fuit tendit: luna, ante urbem Propoetides parte.</content></entry><entry><title>数据公式设置显示</title><url>/2019/03/08/%E6%95%B0%E6%8D%AE%E5%85%AC%E5%BC%8F%E8%AE%BE%E7%BD%AE%E6%98%BE%E7%A4%BA/</url><categories/><tags/><content type="html"> Hugo项目中的数学符号可以通过使用第三方JavaScript库来启用。
In this example we will be using KaTeX
Create a partial under /layouts/partials/math.html Within this partial reference the Auto-render Extension or host these scripts locally. Include the partial in your templates like so: {{ if or .Params.math .Site.Params.math }} {{ partial "math.html" . }} {{ end }} To enable KaTex globally set the parameter math to true in a project&rsquo;s configuration To enable KaTex on a per page basis include the parameter math: true in content files Note: Use the online reference of Supported TeX Functions
Examples Block math: $$ \varphi = 1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\cdots} } } $$</content></entry><entry><title>支持Emoji表情符号</title><url>/2019/03/05/%E6%94%AF%E6%8C%81emoji%E8%A1%A8%E6%83%85%E7%AC%A6%E5%8F%B7/</url><categories/><tags><tag>emoji</tag></tags><content type="html"> 在Hugo项目中可以通过多种方式启用Emoji。
The emojify function can be called directly in templates or Inline Shortcodes.
To enable emoji globally, set enableEmoji to true in your site&rsquo;s configuration and then you can type emoji shorthand codes directly in content files; e.g.
The Emoji cheat sheet is a useful reference for emoji shorthand codes.
N.B. The above steps enable Unicode Standard emoji characters and sequences in Hugo, however the rendering of these glyphs depends on the browser and the platform. To style the emoji you can either use a third party emoji font or a font stack; e.g.
.emoji { font-family: Apple Color Emoji, Segoe UI Emoji, NotoColorEmoji, Segoe UI Symbol, Android Emoji, EmojiSymbols; }</content></entry><entry><title>关于我</title><url>/about.html</url><categories/><tags/><content type="html"> Written in Go, Hugo is an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0. Hugo supports TOML, YAML and JSON data file types, Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes to add rich content. Other notable features are taxonomies, multilingual mode, image processing, custom output formats, HTML/CSS/JS minification and support for Sass SCSS workflows.
Hugo makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
https://github.com/yuin/goldmark https://github.com/alecthomas/chroma https://github.com/muesli/smartcrop https://github.com/spf13/cobra https://github.com/spf13/viper Hugo is ideal for blogs, corporate websites, creative portfolios, online magazines, single page applications or even a website with thousands of pages.
Hugo is for people who want to hand code their own website without worrying about setting up complicated runtimes, dependencies and databases.
Websites built with Hugo are extremely fast, secure and can be deployed anywhere including, AWS, GitHub Pages, Heroku, Netlify and any other hosting provider.
Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</content></entry></search>